他体温有华氏103度(摄氏39.4度)
he's got a temperature of 103.
我们何需关心?
And why do we care?
因为我们是人. 就该关心
Because we're human beings. It's what we do.
他说正参加一个午宴
He said he was at a luncheon memeeting.
你看了他的历史记录?
You took his history?
那家伙有点像 Harpo(美国著名谐星),值得参观
Guy looks like harpo. You should see him.
你问他正读什么书
You asked him what book he's currently reading.
看他试着讲话真是好玩极了
it's hilarious to watch him try and talk.
我问他我能想到的一切
I asked him anything i could think of.
喜欢的颜色:
Favorite color:
"蓝色"
"Bwoo."
最喜爱的
Favorite
甜点上的点缀?
dessert topping?
相信我, 永远都不知道哪一点,是救你命的关键
Trust me,you never know what fact may prove the key to saving your life.
鲜奶油
Whipped cweam.
我问他肯定吗
I asked him if he was sure.
你去哪?
Where are you going?
你是个混蛋
You're an ass.
我知道
I know.
我问你去哪?
Where are you going?
这要么是中毒, 要么是感染,或过敏反应
This is either a toxin,an infection,or an allergic reaction.
猜你已经做了上皮细胞镜检,所以排除过敏
I assume you gave him epi,so that rules out allergies.
使用抗生素以防是感染
Put him on antibiotics in case it's an infection.
如果是中毒, 留他待上一夜
And if it's a toxin,we'll keep him here overnight,
等肿退了, 就遣他回家
let the swelling go down,send him home.
我去看电影了
I'm going to the movies.
你们当中谁是 House ?
Which one of you is house?
瘦瘦的皮肤浅黑的女士
The skinny brunette.
不, 那是 Cameron 医生
No,that's dr. Cameron.
我也瘦. 你怎么知道她名字的?
I'm skinny. How do you know her name?
我曾是你的病人
I was a patient of yours.
噢, 嗯, 如果你想送巧克力, 放在楼下--
Oh,well,if you want to leave the chocolates downstairs--
别动!
Stay!
离他远点
Stay away from him.
震惊, 不是吗?
Shocking,isn't it?
怎么会有人想伤害你呢?
Who'd want to hurt you?
你真可怜
You're pathetic.
根据(胡子)的生长情况
Judging by the growth,
猜我已经不省人事两天了
I'd say I've been unconscious for two days.
你一直坐在那里?
Have you been sitting there the whole time?
没有
No.
根据你发油累积的情况看
Judging by the oily buildup in your hair,
你说谎
I'd say you're lying.
我很害怕
I was scared.
原谅我是出于关心
Pardon me for caring.
我有没有失去什么器官?
Did I lose any organs?
射向你腹部的子弹打穿了你的胃
The bullet to your abdomen pierced your stomach,
伤到了肠子, 最后停在背部肋骨
nicked the bowel,lodged in the posterior rib.
唔, 我一直都说, 如果你要中枪
Well,I always say,if you're gonna get shot,
最好是在医院里
do it in a hospital.
你脖子上那枪--
The one in your neck--
那枪我不记得了
I don't remember that one.
从右侧穿了过去, 对颈静脉造成了严重伤害
Went right through,severed your jugular.
开枪的原来是--
The shooter turns out to be a guy--
不想知道
don't care.
你不想知道为什么有人走进医院,向一名医生开枪?
You don't care why a guy walked into a hospital and shot a doctor?
向你开枪?
Shot you?
我想他的论据是错误的
I assume his reasoning was faulty.
怎么样了?
So what was it?
是感染吗?
Infection?
手术做得很好
The surgery went fine.
你没有术后--
You've had no post-op--
不是我, 那个病人
not me. Patient.
Harpo.
Harpo
你刚刚受了枪伤, House. 你应该休息
You just got shot,house. You should rest.
我中了枪, 诊断起来无趣
I got shot. Diagnostically boring.
肥大的舌头, 换个角度看...无比有趣
Big fat tongue,on the other hand... endlessly entertaining.
活检了他的舌头
We biopsied his tongue.
结果是阴性
and it was negative.
验血结果也是阴性
And the blood tests were negative.
我没说验了血
I didn't say we did blood tests.
不会对舌头进行活检, 除非必须那样做
You don't biopsy a tongue unless you have to biopsy a tongue.
本不需要对舌头活检
And you don't have to biopsy a tongue
除非已进行了一系列常规检查, 却无结果
unless you've already come up with nothing on a routine battery of tests
那些不会使你的病人痛苦的检查
which don't involve torturing your patient.
有新症状吗?
Any new symptoms?
除了颅内压的升高?
Other than the increased intracranial pressure?
有没有猜出我是怎么知道那个的?
Any guesses on how i figured that one out?
你知道下一步会是腰椎穿刺
You knew the next step would be a lumbar puncture.
腰椎穿刺肯定会得出确定答案
A lumbar puncture would almost certainly give us a definitive answer.
既然现在还没有肯定的答案
Since we don't have a definitive answer,
就还没有做穿刺
we must not have done an lp,
而不能做腰穿, 最通常的原因
and the most common reason to not do an lp
就是颅内压升高
is increased intracranial pressure.
他被保安枪击了, 他想--
He was shot by security trying to--
House, 你要--
house,what are you--
house.
House
我去和 Cuddy 谈谈
I'm talking to cuddy.
躺下
Lie down.
你会疼死的
You've got to be in pain.
今天不会
Not today.
今天用着吗啡
Today I'm on morphine.
会把你缝好的伤口撕裂的
You're going to rip your stitches out.
查查 Harpo 的垃圾
Check harpo's trash.
别管那个病人了
Forget about the patient.
算了吧
Come on.
你有点好奇
You're curious.
垃圾?
Trash?
你不知道我指什么
You don't know what I'm talking about
但知道我准没错
but you know it's good.
你不能就这样四处走
You can't just be walking around.
那你阻止我啊
Well,then stop me.
- 你失血--,- 挡住我吧
- You've lost blood-- - physically stop me.
- 你会损害--,- 你不会
- You could damage-- - you can'T.
因为会接触到我身体
Because that would involve physically touching me,
会触发性欲--
and then things would t so sexually charged--
我体型是你两倍
I'm twice your size.
把手拿开
Get your hands off me.
每个活物都得进食
Everything that lives,eats.
吃了东西都会产生废物
Everything that eats,poops.
所以每个器官都有卫生部门
That's why every organ has a sanitation department.
淋巴系统
The lymph system.
不管是什么造成了损害,都会在那倾倒排泄物
Whatever's doing the damage is dumping its waste in there.
那就是你所说的垃圾
That's what you meant by trash.
活检颌下淋巴结
Biopsy the lymph node under the jaw.
很抱歉, 是不近情理, 可实在没别的地方
I'm sorry,I know it's crazy,but there's no other place.
那里是重症监护中心
It's the icu.
表明提供特别护理
It stands for intensive care.
他需要重症特别护理, 你也是
He needs intensive care,so do you.
他该再中一枪
He needs to be shot again.
他被拷在床上
He is handcuffed to his bed.
对他用了镇静剂
He is sedated.
不会再伤到你的了
He's not going to hurt you.
如果你的保安有一点用的话
If your security was any good,
我当初就不会挨枪子儿
I wouldn't have been shot in the first place.
他应当在那里
He is where he's supposed to be.
- 你也该待在那里--,- 谁给我做的手术?
- Where you're supposed to be-- - who did my surgery?
Gillick, 怎么了?
Gillick,why?
要给他送水果蓝吗?
You going to send him a fruit basket?
他搞砸了
He screwed up.
你对唯寇锭(止痛药)成瘾已经够我烦的了
It's annoying enough dealing with your vicodin habit.
别再对吗啡上瘾了
Quit upping your morphine.
我没有
I'm not.
我正在减少剂量
I'm reducing it.
而你不感到疼痛?
And you're not in pain?
我感觉好多了
I'm feeling better.
Gillick 真是太棒了
Gillick is very good.
你的康复期--
Your recovery time--
我的胃疼的要死
my stomach kills me,
脖子悸痛
my neck is throbbing,
但腿却感觉好多了
but my leg feels better.
这太神奇了
That's amazing.
让人难以置信
It's unbelievable.
因为食品药监局不核准枪击用于任何治疗
Since getting shot is not an fda approved treatment for anything,
说明手术中一定出了问题
it means something must have gone wrong in the surgery.
是的, 可怕的... 悲剧性的错误
Yes,terribly...tragically wrong.
享受这个错误吧
Enjoy the mistake.
他肯定弄伤了我的外周神经系统
He must have nicked something in my peripheral nervous system.
如果它减轻了疼痛, 天知道还影响什么?
If it's alleviating pain,who knows what else it's doing?
回重症监护中心去
Get back to the icu
在你的缝线断裂之前
before you rip out your stitches,
我会不得不把你拷在床上的
and I have to chain you to your bed.
为什么你想杀了我?
Why did you try to kill me?
我没有
I didn'T.
枪击难道是个误会
Then the gun thing might have been a mistake.
如果我打算杀了你, 早做到了
If I'd have killed you,it would have been over.
我要你活着
I needed you to live.
因为要看着你被痛苦折磨
Because I want to see you suffer.
把针移开
Get the needle out of there.
他不能呼吸了
He can't breathe.
House.
House
检查结果是阴性
The test was negative.
你这样行么?
Are you sure you want to be doing this?
我很好
I'm fine.
我想
I think
Cameron, 你有我的病历吗?
cameron,you got my records?
一般不公开病人手术记录的
They don't like to release patient's operative notes.
但你手上拿的不正是吗
And yet you're holding them.
还这么小声说话
And whispering.
因为他在睡觉
He's sleeping.
是啊
Yeah.
杀手也需要休息
Killer needs his rest.
不然, 他会暴躁一整天
Otherwise. he's grumpy all day.
嘿! 醒醒
Hey! Wake up.
看看我是怎么救人的
Watch me save a life
可以肯定是某种感染
almost for sure it's some sort of infection.
给他使用了广谱抗菌素
We've got him on broad spectrum antibiotics,
但是病情还在恶化
but it's not even slowing the thing down.
除非找出是哪种感染
Unless we figure out what type of infection,
要不就无法治疗
we can't treat,
而我们无法确定感染类型
and we can't figure out what type
因为不能做腰穿
because we can't do an lp.
做腰穿
Do an lp.
看到我在干什么了吗?
See what I did there?
你杀了我, 我就没法治病救人了
Couldn't have done that if you'd killed me.
能做的话, 两天前就做了
We would have done an lp two days ago if we could have.
可是颅内压太高
But that much pressure,
- 会并发--,- 本该两天前就做腰穿
- something's bound to go-- - we would have done an lp two days ago
但当时刺穿明显弊大于利
if the risks hadn't so obviously outweighed the benefits.
但我们刚刚在他喉咙上戳了一个洞
We just cut a hole in his throat.
利弊的天平倾斜了
The equation has changed.
说得比我还好
Couldn't have put it better myself.
压力...
pressure...
120毫米水柱
120 millimeters h2o,
微弱的变动, 呼吸和脉搏造成的
with small visible excursions related to respiration and pulse.
正常范围内, 不错
Well within normal,that's good.
不, 那才奇怪
No,that's weird.
想听个故事吗?
You want to hear a story?
我有个原则
I have a rule.
开枪打我的人就丧失了权利去--
People who shoot me forfeit the right--
我妻子病了
my wife was sick.
没有医生知道为什么
None of the doctors could figure out why.
噢, 我知道那个故事
Oh,I know this story.
她死了
She died.
所以你选中一名她的治疗医生来枪杀
So you selected one of her doctors to kill,
因为那会使一切又恢复正常
because that would make everything right again.
她没死
She lived.
你把她治好了
You cured her.
治好了她我真遗憾
I'm truly sorry i did that.
在调查她病因的过程中
In the course of investigating her illness,
你让我相信一切事情都是有关的
you convinced me that everything was relevant.
你需要知道事实
You needed the truth.
于是我向你坦白我有外遇
I confessed to you that I'd had an affair.
但那被证明和她的病一点关系都没有
But it turns out that it had nothing to do with why she was sick.
遗传性易患大脑动脉瘤体质
Genetic predisposition to brain aneurysms.
你告诉了她
You told her that.
你还告诉她我有外遇
You also told her about my affair.
所以你被戳穿了
And you caught crap,
她离开了你
she left you,
现在要我来付出代价
and now I've got to pay
就因为你不能把你的小杀手留在裤子里
because you couldn't keep your little killer in your pants.
她自杀了
She killed herself.
哪一类医院会有玻璃墙?
What sort of hospital has glass walls?
那是我丈夫
That's my husband.
真的?
Really?
你以为我只是喜欢看人被针在后背上戳?
You thought I just liked watching people get needles poked in the back?
不是
Nope.
我以为是同事或姐妹
I figured a coworker or a sister.
没想到是妻子
Not wife.
为什么?
Why?
别担心. 我没有羞辱你的意思
Don't worry. It's not insulting.
至少没有对你
At least not to you.
你对那个回答感到满意?
You're satisfied by that answer?
你是 House 医生, 是吗?
You're dr. House,aren't you?
你不会朝我开枪吧?
You're not going to shoot me,are you?
你治好了我的一位朋友
You treated a friend of mine.
她告诉我你只和必须交谈的人交谈
She told me you only talk to people if you have to.
然后你向他们展示你的见解有多么深刻,并以此羞辱他们
And then you insult them while showing off how insightful you are.
7分嫁7分
Sevens marry sevens.
9分配9分
Nines marry nines.
4分凑4分
Fours marry fours.
也许还有变动的机会比如有足够多的钱
Maybe there's some wiggle room if there's enough money,
或者某人怀孕了
or somebody got pregnant.
但是你比你老公至少多得了三分
But you've got at least three points on ur husband,
而你的上衣说明你嫁给他并不是为了钱
and your frock says you didn't do it for the money.
你的胸部又表明你并没有养育过小孩
And your breasts say that you haven't had any kids.
所以你得出结论,我的婚姻是个数学上的错误?
So you figure my marriage is a mathematical error?
数字不会撒谎
Numbers don't lie.
我们无法确定你丈夫是何种感染
We're having trouble finding out what infection your husband has.
最有可能的病因是一种性传染病
The most likely culprit is an std.
你想知道我是不是,和我分数相近的人有外遇
You want to know if I've had an affair with someone closer to my integer.
而我必须告诉你事实, 否则我丈夫就会死
And I have to tell you the truth,or my husband will die.
你朋友是单身吗?
Is your friend single?
不是
No.
我对婚姻很忠诚
And I've always been faithful.
哇
wow.
我觉得没什么大问题
I would've bet money something would go wrong.
我们把他翻过来
Let's rotate him back.
他眼眶出血
he's bleeding into his ocular orbit.
腰穿不会导致这样的情况
Lp wouldn't do this.
后部有太大的压力
Lots of pressure behind.
必须得降低压力
Gotta relieve it.
发生什么了? 他们--他们在干什么?
What's going on? What--what are they doing?
我该走了
I should go.
创口好像被我撕裂了
I seem to have torn my stitches.
你在大厅里晕倒了
You collapsed in the hall.
你的创口被撕裂
Tore your stitches.
我都记得. 我在那
I remember. I was there.
你肠子怎么样? 疼不疼?
How's your gut? It's hurting?
你朝那个卖枪给你妻子的家伙开枪了?
You shoot the guy who sold her the gun?
她把她自己锁在车库里
She locked herself in the garage,
然后她发动了汽车
and she started the car.
你朝卖开车库门装置给你妻子的人开枪了?
You shoot the guy who sold her the garage door opener?
你是个蠢货
You're an ass.
口气很硬啊, 对一个开枪打过你的人
That is a bold position to take,given that I shot you.
枪击只会使你变成白痴
The shooting just makes you an idiot.
你是个蠢货, 因为拉起一面大旗
You're an ass because you're trying to wrap it in the flag,
好像在做什么伟大的事
like you did a good thing.
你是一个蠢货和伪君子
You're an ass and a hypocrite.
你不守常规
You don't believe in rules.
只要你认为是对的, 你什么都会做
You do whatever you think is right.
我也是那么干的
That's all I did.
你是我的榜样
You were my role model.
当心点. 你的旗沾上面包渣了
Watch out.You're getting crumbs on the flag.
要她脸上添光的人不是我
I didn't commit to honor her.
答应永不欺骗她的人不是我
I didn't commit to never lie to her.
那么, 如果你当时闭嘴的话
Well,if you'd kept your mouth shut,
她就不会死, 你也不会挨枪子
she'd be alive,and you wouldn't be shot.
如果你当时把你的"手枪"留在裤子里--
If you'd kept your pistols in your pants--
她的死是我的错
it's my fault she's dead.
我知道的
I know it.
但你为什么就不承认
But why can't you admit
你也许哪怕有那么一丁点的责任呢?
that it's maybe just a little bit yours too?
也许不光是是医学上的错误才会坏事
That maybe it's not just medical mistakes that screw things up.
生活是这样的
Here's how life works.
要么向别人要求道歉
You either get to ask for an apology,
要么你开枪泄愤
or you get to shoot people.
不可两样都做
Not both.
感染不会让你眼珠子弹出来
infections don't make your eyes pop out.
我们该回去
we should get back.
你不是被铐在床上么
You're supposed to be chained to your bed.
还没吃完
I'm not done eating.
肯定有什么出血紊乱
There's got to be some sort of bleeding disorder.
太蠢了
This is really stupid.
瞧, 要是我缝线撑开了
Look,if my stitches pop out again,
有三个医生能救我
I got three doctors to save me.
可能是眼球血管内层薄弱
Could be some sort of weakness in the lining of the ocular veins.
好, 我替你们说
Okay,I'll be you guys.
不可能, 伙计
No way,mate.
这么多血, 不可能是静脉
Too much blood to just be a vein.
不可能, 老兄
No way,hizzie.
如果是动脉, 他会血流不止
If it was an artery,he'd still be bleeding.
事实上, 他会死
Actually,he'd be dead.
他出血的瘘里可能长了肉芽瘤
He could have had a granuloma in his sinuses that bled,
可能是 wegener 肉芽肿造成的,(血管炎, 发生于呼吸道和肾)
which could have been caused by wegener'S.
当把眼球装回去时,如有肿瘤会注意到
I think the surgeon would have noticed a giant growth,while they were sticking the eyeball back in.
舌头和眼睛病了
Tongue and eyes are sick.
鼻子怎么样?
What about the nose?
在两者之间, 它为什么没病?
It's right in between. Why isn't it sick?
不是扩散性的, 是同一病源
So it's not spreading. It's got a common source.
只有什么可能?
Which can only be what?
脑, 但CT没有发现
The brain,except the ct was clean.
检查脑部垃圾, 看藏了什么
Check the brain's trash,see what it's hiding.
脑可没有淋巴系统
The brain doesn't have a lymph system.
我知道
I know.
它的垃圾扔出来
All its garbage just blows off,
被路边的防雪栅栏挡住
gets caught in the snow fence by the side of the road.
你指血脑屏障
You're referring to the blood-brain barrier.
还能是什么？
What else?
检查屏障
Biopsy the barrier.
先根据事实推测, 岂不可靠些?
Wouldn't it be safer to make a few educated guesses first?
试一些安全的治疗
Try some relatively safe treatments?
检查血脑屏障
Biopsy the barrier.
先给他用甲苯哒唑, 以防是寄生虫
But first,start him on mebendazole in case it's a worm.
还有左旋氧氟沙星,以防是逃过第一波抗生素的感染
And levofloxacin in case it's an infection that slipped by the first antibiotic.
再用阿奇霉素, 以防是性病
And azithromycin for stds.
我倒不认为妻子会放任厮混
I really don't think the wife is the kind to be messing around.
我要是娶了她, 肯定不会
If I was married to her,I certainly wouldn't--
house.
house
这病人没结婚, 他是个鳏夫
The patient isn't married. He's a widower.
说真的, 得你自己做复健才有用呢
Really,it's more helpful if you do the prescribed rehab yourself.
我身体没事
My body is fine.
脑子, 却...
My mind,on the other hand...
也许她是女友
maybe she was a girlfriend.
也许她是耍你
Maybe she was just trying to jerk you around.
我问过那层所有的护士了
I spoke to every one of the nurses on that floor.
病人只有6名探视者
The patient had only had six visitors.
2个女子, 没有爱人
Two females,no babes.
他妈妈和阿姨
His mother and his aunt.
也许他们漏掉了谁
So they missed someone.
他们可不是警卫
They're not security.
我手下可没看见我和她在玻璃对面说话
My posse never saw her or me talking on the other side of the glass.
他们忙着救命呢
They were a little busy trying to save the guy's life.
只有一个解释
There's on one possible conclusion.
是幻觉
It was a hallucination.
这你看起来是什么?
What does that look like to you?
Point-six?
0.6?
麻醉剂量?
Anesthesia?
不是
No.
应该是6和一个污点
It's got to be six and a smudge.
就算你是对的
Let's say you'reight.
在外伤后不也很正常么
It wouldn't be that uncommon after trauma.
在失血过多后?
After that much blood loss?
我的感觉如果被损害了
If my perceptions are compromised,
那我的判断也受损
then my judgment is compromised.
要是他妻子告诉我
What if his wife told me
病人刚被狂怒的越南麻风病人咬了如何?
that the patient just got bit by a rabid vietnamese leper?
别介入这个案例了
So pull yourself off the case.
下一个案例呢？
And the next case?
你休息两个星期
You take two weeks.
会恢复
You recover.
要是不呢？
What if I don't?
也许不是枪击造成？
What if it wasn't the shooting?
洞察所有关联的人
The guy who sees connections between everything
怎么看不出枪伤和轻微脑部紊乱的联系？
sees no connection between being shot and minor brain disruptions?
也许是手术？
What if it was the surgery?
也许是你撑破了缝线, 失2品脱的血?
What if it was the fact that you tore out your stitches and lost two pints of blood?
gillick为什么在手术中给我用K他命?,(一种可致迷幻的麻醉剂)
Why did gillick give me ketamine during my surgery?
工作中
Working.
得谈谈
We need to talk.
回去重症护理室, 谁给你松铐的?
Get back to the icu. Who un-cuffed you?
外科医生为什么要用K他命?
Why would a surgeon administer ketamine?
谁让你看你的手术记录?
Who showed you your surgical file?
怎么知道是我的?
How do you know it's mine?
因为你的病人没做手术
Because your patient hasn't had surgery,
你也不关心其他人
and you don't care about anybody else.
我未被施麻醉手术
My anesthesia was almost nonexistent,
却不清醒
and yet I wasn't awake.
出于什么原因
For some reason,
有人将我置于分离性昏迷
somebody decided to put me in a dissociative coma
而不是仅仅让我昏过去
instead of just putting me out.
有充足的理由使用
There are plenty of reasons to use--
好吧
fine.
我自己去问手术医生真相
I'll go beat the truth out of my surgeon.
Gillick, 对吗?
Gillick,right?
奏效了
It worked.
在德国有一个医疗机构
There's a clinic in germany.
他们诱发昏迷来治疗慢性疼痛
They've been treating chronic pain by inducing comas,
让脑子能重新启动
and letting the mind basically reboot itself.
有50%的可能, 你的疼痛会回来
There's about a 50% chance your pain will come back.
意味着还有50%机会, 不会
Which of course means there is a 50% chance that it won'T.
你没有权利--
You had no right--
来治好你?
to heal you?
你摆弄我的脑子
You messed with my brain.
你为什么心烦?
Why are you so upset?
你有什么神经症状吗?
Are you experiencing any neurological symptoms?
晕眩, 震颤, 幻觉?
Dizziness,tremors,hallucinations?
没有
No.
这是原则问题
It's a point of principle.
检查呈阴性
Test was negative.
栅栏处没有垃圾
No trash against the fence.
你的腿真的好了?
Is your leg really better?
别担心, 总有地方坏了
Don't worry,I'm sure something else is wrong.
确实找到了血
We did find blood.
在那一边?
On which side?
错的那边
The wrong side.
第一桩有意义的发现
First thing that makes sense.
错的一边是错的
The wrong side's the wrong side.
没有意义
It can't make sense.
搅乱脑子
It'd mess with his brain.
不会导致高烧
Wouldn't cause fever.
他最近睡得很多
He's been sleeping a lot lately.
你担心了?
You worried?
我给他换了点药
I marked a change of meds on his chart.
异物
Foreign object.
身体想摆脱掉
Body wants to get rid of it.
导致高烧
It causes the fever.
血液中的异物?
Blood's a foreign object?
在大脑内皮层里, 即
in the brain lining,it is.
血恶液质说明有癌症
Blood dyscrasia means cancer.
找到它
Find it.
- 所有的检查,- 都是阴性
- All the tests-- - have been negative.
你家的垃圾桶满了怎么办?
What do you do if your trash cans are full?
用邻居的垃圾桶
You use your neighbors' trash cans.
可要是外面灯亮着
Except it's still light outside.
邻居会看到
Your neighbor will see you.
所以你走后门, 跑进小巷
So you go out the back way,into an alley,
把垃圾扔在邻家车库旁
and drop off your trash by their garage.
去检查胸腔的淋巴系统
We'll check the lymphatic system in the chest.
你从巷子里的垃圾桶就推导出了?
You got that from trash cans in the alley?
舌头的唾液腺
The saliva glands from the tongue
和肺部的淋巴系统相连
are connected to the lymphatic system in the lungs.
这是下一个邻近的淋巴系统
It's the next lymphatic system over.
是的
Yeah.
去查肺淋巴液
Go get lung lymph.
他怎么会想到的
How did he know that?
他要是不聪明, 我就不会雇用他了
I uldn't have hired him if he wasn't smart.
是
Right.
你只是敬重他
Because you have nothing but respect for him.
或许他知道答案
Maybe he knew the answer
因为提问
because the question
不如你想的那么狡猾
wasn't nearly as tricky as you thought.
或许不是他变聪明了
Maybe he's not getting smarter.
而是你变笨了
You're getting dumber.
你假装颠覆体制
You pretend to buck the system.
你假装做个叛逆者
Pretend to be a rebel.
声称仇恨规则
You claim to hate rules.
但你所做所为不过是,用你的规则来替代这个社会的
But all you do is substitute your own rules for society'S.
这是个简单美妙的规则
And it's a nice,simple rule.
说出直率正直的真相
Tell the blunt,honest truth
用最赤裸裸, 黑暗的方式
in the starkest,darkest way.
会怎样就怎样
And what will be will be.
该怎样就怎样
What will be should be.
所有其他人都是懦夫
And everyone else is a coward.
但你错了
But you're wrong.
不把别人当傻瓜并不是怯懦
It's not cowardly to not call someone an idiot.
人们不仅仅出于友善而表现得谨慎礼貌
People aren't tactful or polite just because it's nice.
他们这样, 因为尚有一丝的谦恭在
They do it because they've got an ounce of humility.
因为他们知道会犯错误
Because they know that they will make mistakes,
知道他们的行为会有后果
and they know that their actions have consequences.
他们知道后果是自己的错误造成
And they know that those consequences are their fault.
你为什么如此不人性, house?
Why do you want so bad not to be human,house?
噢, 他醒着
Oh,he's awake.
House, 得跟你谈谈
House,we need to talk to you.
你怎知道我醒着?
How the hell did you know i was awake?
你睡着时鼻孔喷火
Your nostrils flare when you sleep.
不, 才没有
No,they do not.
好, 我说谎了
Fine,I'm lying.
检查都是阴性
Test was negative.
你知道?
You knew?
习惯的力量
Force of habit.
未发现癌症
showed no cancer.
没道理他高烧到103度
No reason why he's got a fever of 103,
没道理他的舌头放不进嘴里
and no reason why his tongue won't fit in his mouth.
他做完手术. Chase 照看他
He's post-op.Chase is getting him up and around.
你手术后起来动动很重要
It's important that you're up asap after surgery.
觉得你能小便？
You think you can urinate?
涨大了!
It's getting bigger!
什么, 你...
What,you're...
你勃起了?
getting aroused?
不! 不是那一部分
No!Not that part.
哦, 天, 很疼
Oh,god,it hurts.
停不下来
It's not stopping.
手术没有发现动脉破裂
surgeons found no evidence of a burst artery.
这么多血不会无缘无故
The blood had to come from somewhere.
你被喷了一身
You took a shower in it.
创伤?
Trauma?
你觉得有人溜进来踢他的蛋蛋
You think someone snuck in here just to kick him in the jewels?
戳他的眼睛, 还吹大他的舌头?
And poke out his eye,and swell up his tongue?
继续骑
Keep riding.
我和理疗师打赌说我周五前能骑100公里
I got a bet with my physio that I can do 100 klicks by friday.
肾脏出血?
What about blood from the kidneys?
血从肾脏进入膀胱, 然后流入尿道
Kidneys drain into the bladder,which drains into the ureter.
不可能灌到阴囊里
There's no way it would mess with the scrotum.
是啊
Yeah.
基本人体构造
Basic human anatomy.
换言之, 我认为问题在别处
Therefore,I think it's safe to assume that the problem lies elsewhere.
这个病例反正也不符合常理
But given that this case doesn't make any kind of sense whatsoever,
也许应该怀疑他的基本构造
maybe we should even question the basics.
也许他不是人类
Maybe he's not human.
应该说解剖结构缺陷, 不过..,也不除他是非人
an anatomical defect would seem more likely,but let's not rule that one out.
更合理的说法, 他是人
Even more likely,he is human,
解剖结构也正常, 但他有睾丸癌
his anatomy is where it's supposed to be,but he has testicular cancer.
检查过癌症
we tested for cancer.
我们检查了胸部的淋巴系统
we tested the lymph system in his chest.
手术未发现增大
surgeons found no growth.
手术人员并不会留意这些
surgeons were just trying to put everything back where it was.
他们不是每项都做
They weren't doing an inventory.
他走运了也说不定
May have been lucky.
如果不能早期发现睾丸癌, 会死人的
If you don't catch testicular cancer early,it kills.
可能侵蚀了某些血管
Probably eroded some vessel.
是, 我知道
Yeah,I know.
问题是为何我没想到
The question is why i didn't think of it.
眼球弹出是个奇怪的表征
Eyes popping out is a rather odd presentation.
反之, 阴囊爆炸就...
Sack blowing up,on the other hand...
如果都能自己想出来,你就不需要折磨团队了
if you could think of everything yourself,you wouldn't need a team to annoy.
我没注意到基本的解剖
I screwed up some basic anatomy.
没有把睾丸爆炸和睾丸联系起来
And I missed connecting a testicular explosion with a testicular problem.
以前我不可能这样,都是cuddy乱搞我的大脑
You think there's any way i would have done that before cuddy messed with my brain?
她只是在帮你, 而且奏效了
She was trying to help you,and it worked.
是啊, 我跑的像一阵风
Yeah,I can run like the wind,
却失去了思考
but I can't think.
现在转行当运动员也太老了点
And seeing as how i'm too old to become a professional athlete,
好像是多年蓄意的恶作剧
it looks to me as if she screwed me over big time.
你不想要健康的腿
You don't want a healthy leg.
又来了
Oh,here we go.
如果你生活美满, 身体健康
If you've got a good life,if you're healthy,
你就没借口愤世, 没借口憎恨生活
you've got no reason to bitch.No reason to hate life.
逻辑有漏洞
Here's the flaw in your argument.
如果我享受憎恨生活,说明我不恨生活, 我享受生活
If I enjoy hating life,I don't hate life.I enjoy it.
你不能按正常逻辑
I didn't say it was rational.
艾滋病测试的准确率为99%
Hiv testing is 99% accurate,
意思是有些人测试阳性
which means there are some people who test positive
在末日的恐惧中生活数月
who live with their own impending doom for months,
甚至数年, 然后发现自己没事
or years,before finding out everything's okay.
奇怪的是, 大多数人没有欣喜,甚至也不生气
Weirdly,most of them don't react with happiness.Or even anger.
他们只是沮丧
They get depressed.
并非他们想死
Not because they wanted to die,
而是他们已经根据疾病把自己归类
but because they've defined themselves by their disease.
突然, 用来归类的依据失效了
Suddenly,what made them them isn't real.
我没把自己归为瘸子
I don't define myself by my leg.
不, 你的归类更过分
No,you have taken it one step further.
你对待残疾的办法是
The only way you could come to terms with your disability
让它显得无足轻重
was to somehow make it mean nothing.
这样你就得重新归类
So you had to redefine everything.
你放弃了一切生理的-
You have dismissed anything physical.
只留下冰冷的, 可以计算的信息
Anything not coldly,calculatingly intellectual.
为什么帮她说话?
Why are you protecting her?
因为她没做错什么
Because she's done nothing wrong.
你觉得她对我所做的没什么?
You're completely comfortable with what she did to me?
是的
Yeah,I am.Yeah.
你对道德抉择从不轻松
You agonize over moral choices.
你不会对任何东西无所谓
You're not completely comfortable with anything
除非你先考虑到方方面面
until you've taken days to get your head around every possible side.
我6小时前才发现她对我做的
I've known what she did for six hours.
你好像知道好几天了?
How come you're acting like you've known for days?
我得了什么?
What do I have?
你没病
You're not sick.
我得了什么?
What do I have?
你要冷静
You need to calm down.
我的大脑废了! 就是这样!
I have my brain!And that's it!
我们试图帮你
We were trying to help you.
没人"试图"捣乱, 直接动手即可
Yeah,nobody tries to screw up!They just do.
你失控了, 你在用吗啡--
You were out of control.You were shooting morphine--
我有能力帮助别人!
I can make people better!
你们俩决定用跑步能力来交换
And you two decide to trade that for jogging shoots.
如果有副作用, 我们可以查个清楚--
If you're suffering from side effects,then we can look at that--
你太注重肉体
you value the physical so much.
我们用简单易懂的语言
Let me put this in terms you can understand.
你真行
You're unbelievable.
甚至在愤怒和恐惧的时候
Even when you're out of your mind with anger and fear,
还是有条有理
you still couch it in logical terms.
你产生幻觉?
Are you hallucinating?
是的, 我有幻觉!
Yeah,I'm hallucinating!
不, 我说现在
No,I mean right now.
你有幻觉?
Are you hallucinating?
你怎么知道我...
How did you know I was...
你对我大叫大嚷
you were yelling at me.
你叫我wilson
You were calling me wilson.
没有
No.
你现在醒了, house.
You're losing it,house.
我从没叫过wilson名字
I never call wilson by his name.
噢, 是啊
Oh,yeah,right.
幻觉的人要告诉他的幻觉对象,发生了什么
The hallucinator is going to tell the hallucinatee what happened.
你没出现在幻觉中, Wilson才是
You're not the hallucinatee.Wilson was the hallucinatee.
你这是不是有点避重就轻?
You think maybe you're focusing on the wrong thing here?
Cuddy的办公室
Cuddy's office was the hallucinatee.
还有洗手间
The bathroom was the hallucinatee.
洗手间, 明白了
Bathroom.It figures.
明白什么?
What figures?
你尿床了
You wet your bed.
妈的
Damn it.
测试阴性
Test was negative.
不
No.
Afp蛋白和β-HCG检查排除睾丸癌
Afp and beta hcg say no testicular cancer.
从头来, 我们排除了每一种可能
So,let's recap.We've just ruled out everything.
不符合常理
Which doesn't make sense.
所以, 答案必然也不符合常理
So the answer has to be something that doesn't make sense.
做膀胱镜检查, 并且确保他是人类
Do a cystoscopy. Make sure he's human.
检查结果是否定的
Test was negative.
他不是人类?
For him being human?
各个部位都在正常的位置
Everything was right where it's supposed to be.
所有的通道都通向正常的位置
All the tubes go where they're supposed to go.
最可能的是细菌性前列腺炎
Most likely scenario is some kind of bacterial prostatitis.
查查他父亲是不是弓着背
Find out if his father hunche
尿尿有麻烦?
his father have trouble peeing?
他父亲和亲生母亲上床?
His father have sex with his own mother?
任何一条被言中, 就可以假设你是对的
If the answers to any of these questions is yes,assume you're right.
如果都没有说中
If the answers are no,
还是假设你对,但要检查前列腺淋巴以防万一
assume you're right,but biopsy some prostate lymphs just to be sure.
可是...
But...
那只能切开他的腹部
then we'd have to cut through his stomach.
明显他有出血的问题, 这种手术可能--
And since he's clearly got a bleeding problem,this kind of surgery might--
他不是"明显"有问题
he doesn't clearly have anything.
我怎么到这里的?
How did I get here?
你说什么?
What are you talking about?
我起先在icu.
I was in the icu.
然后就和你们一起下楼梯
And then I was coming down these stairs with you guys.
中间发生了什么?
What happened in between?
我不记得怎么到这里
I don't remember how I got here.
我不能继续跟病例
I'm taking myself off my case.
你的病人在深度监护, 连续两天发烧--
Your patient's in critical care.He's had a fever unabated for two--
我变的糊涂
I'm losing my mind.
有时头昏
I'm having blackouts.
你说了没有--
You said you weren't having any--
我撒谎了
I lied.
如果你想这样来吓唬我, 你得逞了
If you are doing this to scare me,you made your point.
下次你被枪打, 我保证只管治枪伤
Next time you get shot,I promise to only treat the bullet wounds.
我放弃病例
I'm off the case.
我进来的时候为什么跳起来?
Why did you jump up when I came in?
我以为你又来找我麻烦
I thought you were going to attack me again.
又来?
Again?
是, 你对我破口大骂
Yeah,you were in my face.
- 你还--,- 不, 我没有
You were-- --no,I wasn'T.
你和Wilson一起进来--
You came in here with wilson and--
那是幻觉
that was a hallucination.
不, 你--
No,you--
说明这也是幻觉
which means this is a hallucination.
怎样才能分辨是不是真实的?
how can I tell what's real and what's not?
看上去都一样
Everything looks the same.
听起来一样
Sounds the same.
尝起来也一样
Tastes the same.
看来你根本不想问我
Seems like I'd be the last person you'd want to ask.
当然不想
Why not?
明显你不在这里
You're obviously not here.
我也不在这里
I'm obviously not here.
这些都是我头脑里的
Which means this is a creation of my mind,
所以我其实在自问自答
which means I'm really just asking myself.
如果你是在跟自己说话,那些解释都不必要
Well,if you're talking to yourself,that's a lot of unnecessary explanation.
嘿, 我是想搞清楚
Hey,I'm trying to work this out.
有予有求才行, 即使在我脑子里
That requires give and take,even in my own mind.
有什么问题?
What was the question?
怎样才能分辨是不是真的?
How can I tell what's real?
有所谓吗?
Does it matter?
我没问这个问题
That doesn't sound like something I'd ask.
好吧
All right.
你担心的是在真实的世界里,根据不真实的信息行动
Your concern is at if you act in the real world based on information that's not real,
造成后果的不可预料
the results are impossible to foresee.
你不就是
With you so far.
但是信息本身并非有害
But information is incapable of harm in and of itself.
不管一个念头是好是坏
Ideas are neither good nor bad,
只有当我们实施才有用
but merely as useful as what we do with them.
只有行动能造成伤害
Only actions can cause harm.
这像我说的话
That sounds like me.
所以你不要做任何事
So you do nothing.
控制自己不要行动
You refrain from taking any actions.
继续像往常一样冒出主意
Continue to throw out your ideas as you always would,
如果这些主意是基于错误前提
but if they're based on faulty assumptions,
你的团队会指正你
your team will point that out.
不会对他们造成伤害
They won't do anything that could hurt him.
所以我要信任团队
So I trust my team.
检查都是否定的
Test was negative.
前列腺没有出血
No blood in the prostate.
没有构造异常
No structural abnormalities.
如果某事无法解释
If something doesn't make sense,
这表示什么?
what does that mean?
不是玩修辞
It's not rhetorical.
我需要你们回答我的问题,不管它多么的明显
I need your input on everything I ask,no matter how obvious it might seem.
表示你错了
It means you're wrong.
表示你的前提假设是错的
It means one of your assumptions is wrong.
因为如果某事无法解释, 它就不是真实的
Because if something doesn't make sense,it can't be real.
我们的前提条件是?
So,what are our assumptions?
我们没有前提, 只是猜测然后检查
We don't have any.We're just guessing on testing.
我们假设检查结果都是正确的
We assume the tests are right.
我们重新检查了两次
We've already redone them.
从更基本的地方考虑
Twice.Let's go more basic.
有什么比检查结果还要基本的?
What's more basic than the test results?
检查本身
The tests themselves.
活组织切片检查包括那些环节?
What does a biopsy consist of?
取样
You take a sample.
什么叫样本?
Define sample.
你认为有问题部位的一小片代表性组织
It's a small representative piece of whatever you think is the problem.
走到岸边, 舀一杯水
you go down to the shore,you fill a cup of water.
杯子里没有鱼
It's got no fish in it.
难道可以证明海里没有鱼?
Does that mean no fish in the ocean?
我们可以再做一次检查
We can do another biopsy.
那样我们只会舀起另一杯水,我们需要潜到海底
We could fill another cup of water.We gotta dive in.
我们必须找到里面到底有什么
We gotta see what's actually in there.
不能动手术, 他有出血问题
We can't operate.He's got a bleeding problem.
我们假设他有出血问题
We assume he's got a bleeding problem.
因为他从不该出血的地方出血
Yeah,because he bled from where he wasn't supposed to bleed,
导致身体的一部分爆裂
causing parts of his body to blow up.
如果我们这个假设是正确的
Assuming that crazy assumption is correct,
动手术等于杀死他
if we operate on him,we'll kill him.
那如果我们能找到一个办法
What if we could find a way to do this surgery
可以只开一个小口?
without giving him more than a paper cut?
你们想让机器人给我做手术?
You want to let a robot operate on me?
科技发展很快
The technology is amazing.
机器能放大十倍, 那就是十倍的精确
It magnifies everything ten times.It's ten times the accuracy.
不行, 我更信任人
No way.I want a person.
会有人来操纵...
A person will be controlling--
人类靠不住
people suck.
是人使你从一个大舌头变得
People have turned you from a guy with a swollen tongue
一只眼, 一个蛋蛋,还有一张打满纱布的脸
into a guy with one eye,one ball,and a stapled-on face.
如果你希望有人在你哭泣入眠时抱着你
If you want someone to hold you while you cry yourself to sleep at night,
找个暖和一点, 温柔一点的
choose warm and soft.
如果要人给你作首诗
If you want someone to write you a poem,
找个更为敏感的独行者
pick the sensitive loner.
如果想找个能做好事的
But if all you care about is that something's done right,
请找铁头人
pick the guy with the metal head.
没门
No way.
你说没门也不行
No way,no way.
在你说没门前你得看看,它是怎么工作的, 来吧
You gotta see this thing in action before you say no way.Come on.
House, 你想干嘛?
House.What are you doing?
没想干嘛
Nothing.
我不会做任何事情
I'm not doing anything.
只是发表看法
Just throwing out ideas.
我想你该找个轮椅, 把他推到手术室去
I think you should put him in a wheelchair,take him down to the O.R.
可能我是有点疯了
But I may be out of my mind.
放松, Cameron
Relax,cameron.
我不会伤到你的
I'm not going to cut you.
只是想演示下它的能力
I just want to show what this puppy can do.
它可以切开只有一毫米的口子
It can make one-millimeter incisions.
你知道这有多小么?
You know how small that is?
在米制单位里已经很小了
It's small even in metric.
如果我做了什么奇怪的事
If I do something that doesn't make sense,
对你做了的话, 阻止我
even to you,stop me.
很精巧, 不是么?
Delicate,no?
House.
House
痛吗?
Does that hurt?
看够了没?
Seen enough?
还没
No.
这可不是个问句
That wasn't a question.
你要么做手术, 要么去死
You either do this,or you die.
你浪费了你的生命
You've wasted your life.
没错
Yeah.
我应该多花点时间去找个值得射杀的人
If only I'd spent more time dedicating myself to finding someone worthy to shoot.
如果我那时杀了你, 也不在乎么?
If I had killed you,would it have mattered?
对我来说, 不
Not to me.
有笔么?
Have you got a pen?
你不在乎生死?
You don't care if you live or die?
我还活着所以在乎
I care because I live.
我死了想在乎也不可能了
I can't care if I'm dead.
我不想和你玩文字游戏
I don't want to hear semantics.
你这个不懂语义学的混蛋
You anti-semantic bastard.
如果世界没有了你这种智慧,会有人在乎么?
Would anybody care that the world lost that wit?
我正忙着呢
Working here.
没关系, 你什么也不用说
That's all right.You don't have to say anything.
让我进入你的潜意识
Just let me soak into your subconscious.
你认为唯一有意义的真理是
You think that the only truth that matters
那些可以衡量的真理
is the truth that can be measured.
好意可不算
Good intentions don't count.
心里想的不算
What's in your heart doesn't count.
关爱也不算
Caring doesn't count.
但是一个男人一生的价值可以用
But a man's life can be measured
他死时有多少人落泪来衡量
by how many tears are shed when he dies.
只是因为你不能衡量它们
Just because you can't measure them,
只是因为你不想衡量它们
just because you don't want to measure them,
并不代表那不存在
doesn't mean it's not real.
这解释不通
That does not make sense.
即是我是错的
And even if I'm wrong,
你还是那么痛苦
you're still miserable.
你真的认为生命的目的
Did you really think that your life's purpose
是牺牲自己而不求回报
was to sacrifice yourself and get nothing in return?
这不对
No.
你相信做任何事情都不该有目的
You believe there's no purpose to anything.
包括你拯救的生命, 以及不能拯救的
Even the lives you save,you dismiss.
你做了件高尚的事, 可你贬低它,说没有任何意义
You turn the one decent thing in your life,and you taint it,strip it of all meaning.
你只是徒然地痛苦
You're miserable for nothing.
我不知道你为什么还想活着
I don't know why you'd want to live.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我知道问题在哪了
I know what's wrong.
House, 快出去, 你没有消过毒
House,get out of here.You're not sterile.
他会好起来的
He'll be fine.
太好了
great.
他得了什么病?
What's he got?
为什么你们从来没试着,让我不接手这个病例?
How come you guys have never tried to yank me off this case?
我一直存在幻觉
I'm having hallucinations.
思维空白
Blackouts.
你总有点疯狂, 但你总是对的
But you're always insane,and you're always right.
我总是到最后才是正确的
I'm almost always eventually right.
你不可能知道什么时候是"最后"
You have no way of knowing when "eventually" is.
每次我有什么想法了
Every time I've had an epiphany on this one,
你们唯命是从
you guys were right on board.
不挑战我的观点, 也不做任何辩解
No challenges,no need to explain.
没什么恶意, 但是
No offense,but
要么你们越来越聪明了,要么就是我越来越笨了
either you guys are getting smarter,or I'm getting dumber.
我们和你工作那么久了, 知道...
We've worked with you long enough to know--
我在你们进门前就知道检查结果了
I know the test results even before you enter the room.
我们存在一样的意识
We have identical knowledge.
这怎么可能?
How is that possible?
你错了
You're wrong.
如果有什么事情说不通
If something doesn't make sense,
一定是你们的某个假设错了
one of your assumptions has to be wrong.
因为如果解释不通, 现实中就不可能发生
Because if something doesn't make sense,it can't be real.
如果假设这并不是现实, 会怎样?
But what if the faulty assumption is that it's real?
House, 你有点迷糊了
House,you're losing it.
我早迷糊了
I've lost it.
为什么阻止我?
Why did you stop me?
因为我觉得你要杀了他
Because I think you're going to kill him.
不, 你不是觉得
No,you don't think that.
而是知道我要这么做
You know it.
因为你存在于我的思维中
Because you're in my head.
只要错觉有合理的解释,我就不会醒来
As long as the delusion makes sense,my mind lets it go on.
我必须要让一切没法解释
I have to make it not make sense.I have to...
使这些不再能欺骗我的大脑
push it past the point where it can trick my mind.
喂, 喂
Hey,hey.
如果这是个噩梦的话, 你会醒过来
If this is a nightmare,you're gonna wake up.
如果是现实, 你可是在杀人
If it's real,you're killing a man.
还有一种可能是我已经死了
It's also possible that I may already be dead.
但我不相信死后有什么灵魂
But I don't believe in the after life.
House, 回到病房去
House,go back to your room.
如果这是幻觉, 也挺好的
If this is a hallucination,it's a good one.
你能感受到疼痛, 你能走路...
You're pain free,you can walk--
这不是真实的, 所以, 这些都没什么意义
it's not real.Therefore,it's meaningless.
我需要有意义的东西
I want meaning.
我的上帝
Oh,god.
再见
Goodbye.
- 他中枪了,- 两发
he was shot.--Twice.
腹部一枪, 脖子一枪
Once in the abdomen,once in the neck.
-嗨,-没事的
Hello.--It's going to be okay.
你会没事的
You're gonna be okay.
你什么都不知道
You don't know nothing.
告诉Cuddy
Tell cuddy...
给我用K他命
I want ketamine.